KIRILL MARCHENKO

Fullstack Developer & BSc Computing Student

I am a Fullstack Developer who graduated from High School in Ukraine in 2022. Momentarily, I live in Prague, where I am studying BSc in Computing at Prague City University – a highly-ranked, private institution offering British quality, contemporary education.

Since childhood, I have had a strong passion for programming and have spent much of my free time learning programming languages such as Javascript and Java. I had the privilege of learning from a mentor as well as teaching myself, which allowed me to create numerous projects to challenge and improve my skills. I was also fortunate enough to meet a group of like-minded people who shared my passion for programming. Together we worked on a variety of projects, which developed my teamwork skills and gave me invaluable experience. This period of my life has shaped my personal skills and solidified my aptitude for programming.

As a programmer, I hope to learn, invent and implement new strategies to achieve advanced goals. I also look forward to solving a variety of challenges, gaining experience and a better understanding of my field of interest.

Professional Experience Web Developer

Daily Distro LLC - USA

September 2023 - June 2024



- Built and maintained client portal using React and Wordpress to deploy to pages. Portal also has nodejs server on digitalocean.
- Made a usable and accessible UI for the customers.
- Sucesefully implemented the task requirements from the client.
- Assured that all the requites from the client were met.
- Discussed the work results and future steps.
- Additionally, developed a couple of smaller projects for the client.

Application Developer

Freelance - Ukraine

December 2022 - June 2023



- Developed large application using Java and SqLite.
- Making a usable and accessible UI for the customer using Java frameworks: JavaFX, JDBC and Hibernate.

CONTACTS

Phone:

- +420792448178
- +380983645564

Email:

kirillmarchenko413@gmail.com

LinkedIn:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/kirill-marchenko-b51468236/

GitHub:

https://github.com/SDT413

Telegram:

https://t.me/D_K413

WhatsApp:

+380983645564

EDUCATION

BSc Computing

September 2022 -

Present Prague City

University Prague, Czech

Republic Prague 1, Czech

Languages

- English Fluent
- Ukrainian Native

Skills

- HTML&CSS, Javascript, Typescript and Tailwind CSS
- React and Next.js
- Node.js, Express and Sequilize.
- Client/Server WebSockets
- JWT tokens.
- PostgreSQL, MySQL, SQLite, MongoDB
- Ubuntu server(Nginx) and filesystem interaction.
- Redux toolkit and Tanstack query.
- Git, Github, Gitlab.

^{*}references are in the end of the second page

KIRILL MARCHENKO

Prague 1, Czech Republic | (+(420) 792-448-178 | kirillmarchenko413@gmail.com

Skills

Personal Projects



- Clients thefbamachine: Clients portal for thefbamachine.co. Shows proposals to users, has a payment page and many other pages for portal employees.
 ProjectLink: https://clients.thefbamachine.co/
- Spotify clone: This project demonstrates the design and implementation of a music streaming application's user interface, inspired by popular platforms like Spotify. The focus was on creating a clean, intuitive and visually appealing interface.

GitHub: https://github.com/SDT413/spotify-clone ProjectLink: https://spotify-clone413.vercel.app/

 Coffee shop: Responsive coffee shop for training of commercial development with React typescript, Redux Toolkit and Next.js. With Routes, React and custom hooks. Shop follows the classic single application structure. Has implemented backend part on Spring with postgreSql database. Custom written Rest API, services and repositories.

GitHub: https://github.com/SDT413/coffee-shop

• Geograpy Minigames: is a game about solving problems on the map with limited time, offering the player the opportunity to try four game modes that provide different interactions with the map. The essence in all modes is the same: answer the question/search goal by selecting the corresponding object on the map. In the player's search, they will be assisted by the helper function, which allows the player to narrow the scope of the search on the map to a certain circle while sacrificing part of the time to solve the problem.

GitHub: https://github.com/SDT413/GeographyMinigames ProjectLink: https://sdt413.github.io/GeographyMinigames/

• Covid-19 Dashboard: Built a real-time Covid-19 dashboard application using Python, which transforms data into diagrams and charts for easy representation.

GitHub Profile: https://github.com/SDT413

Portfolio: https://sdt413.github.io/portfolio-next/

- Spring Boot.
- JUnit tests and Mockito.
- Spring Data JPA.
- Maven and Gradle build systems.
- Spring OAuth2.
- JUnit tests and Mockito
- Hibernate entities.
- Spring Security.



References

- Nikita, One of freelance client, +380 (95) 207 93 09, contact on WhatsApp
- David Petryca, MA. The Lecturer and specialist in Web Development of the Prague city university, david.p@praguecollege.cz, contact directly
- Ahmet Vargelen, MA. The Lecturer of the Prague city university and specialist in project management, ahmet.v@praguecityuniversity.cz, contact directly